His people needed a leader. He gave them a champion.
Invictus is a drama, history film directed by Clint Eastwood.
Newly elected President Nelson Mandela knows his nation remains
racially and economically divided in the wake of apartheid.
Believing he can bring his people together through the universal language of sport, Mandela rallies South Africa's
rugby union team as they make their historic run to the 1995 Rugby World Cup Championship match.
Nelson Mandela, played by Morgan Freeman.
Francois Pienaar, played by Matt Damon.
Jason Tshabalala, played by Tony Kgoroge.
Linga Moonsamy, played by Patrick Mofokeng.
Hendrick Booyens, played by Matt Stern.
Etienne Feyder, played by Julian Lewis Jones.
Invictus is a 2009 docudrama sports film directed by Clint
Eastwood and starring Morgan Freeman and Matt Damon.
It is the third collaboration between Eastwood and Freeman after Unforgiven (1992) and Million Dollar
Baby (2004), and the first between Eastwood and Damon, followed by Hereafter (2010).
The story is based on the 2008 John Carlin book Playing the Enemy: Nelson Mandela and the Game That Made
a Nation about the events in South Africa before and during the 1995 Rugby World Cup.
The national team, the Springboks, were not expected to perform well, the team having only recently returned to high-level international
competition following the dismantling of apartheid—the country was hosting the World Cup, thus earning an automatic entry.
Freeman portrays South African President Nelson Mandela while Damon played Francois
Pienaar, the captain of the Springboks, the South Africa rugby union team.
Invictus was released in the United States on 11 December 2009.
The film is named after a poem of the same name by British poet William Ernest
Henley, which serves as a central plot element in the film.
The film was met with positive critical reviews and earned Academy Award
nominations for Freeman (Best Actor) and Damon (Best Supporting Actor).
The film grossed $122.2 million on a budget of $50–60 million.
The film explores themes of sports, stadium, south africa, apartheid, idealism.
The tone is emotional.